<resources>
    <string name="app_name">My Classic Car</string>
    <string-array name="engUnits">
        <item>CID</item>
        <item>Liter</item>
        <item>CC</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="odo">
        <item>Miles</item>
        <item>KM</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="engConfiguration">
        <item>1 Cyl</item>
        <item>L2</item>
        <item>L3</item>
        <item>L4</item>
        <item>L5</item>
        <item>L6</item>
        <item>L8</item>
        <item>Flat 4</item>
        <item>Flat 6</item>
        <item>V2</item>
        <item>V4</item>
        <item>V5</item>
        <item>V6</item>
        <item>V8</item>
        <item>V10</item>
        <item>V12</item>
        <item>V16</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="years">
        <item>Year</item>
        <item>1999</item>
        <item>1998</item>
        <item>1997</item>
        <item>1996</item>
        <item>1995</item>
        <item>1994</item>
        <item>1993</item>
        <item>1992</item>
        <item>1991</item>
        <item>1990</item>
        <item>1989</item>
        <item>1988</item>
        <item>1987</item>
        <item>1986</item>
        <item>1985</item>
        <item>1984</item>
        <item>1983</item>
        <item>1982</item>
        <item>1981</item>
        <item>1980</item>
        <item>1979</item>
        <item>1978</item>
        <item>1977</item>
        <item>1976</item>
        <item>1975</item>
        <item>1974</item>
        <item>1973</item>
        <item>1972</item>
        <item>1971</item>
        <item>1970</item>
        <item>1969</item>
        <item>1968</item>
        <item>1967</item>
        <item>1966</item>
        <item>1965</item>
        <item>1964</item>
        <item>1963</item>
        <item>1962</item>
        <item>1961</item>
        <item>1960</item>
        <item>1959</item>
        <item>1959</item>
        <item>1958</item>
        <item>1957</item>
        <item>1956</item>
        <item>1955</item>
        <item>1954</item>
        <item>1953</item>
        <item>1952</item>
        <item>1951</item>
        <item>1949</item>
        <item>1949</item>
        <item>1948</item>
        <item>1947</item>
        <item>1946</item>
        <item>1945</item>
        <item>1944</item>
        <item>1943</item>
        <item>1942</item>
        <item>1941</item>
        <item>1940</item>
        <item>1939</item>
        <item>1938</item>
        <item>1937</item>
        <item>1936</item>
        <item>1935</item>
        <item>1934</item>
        <item>1933</item>
        <item>1932</item>
        <item>1931</item>
        <item>1930</item>
        <item>1929</item>
        <item>1928</item>
        <item>1927</item>
        <item>1926</item>
        <item>1925</item>
        <item>1924</item>
        <item>1923</item>
        <item>1922</item>
        <item>1921</item>
        <item>1920</item>
        <item>1919</item>
        <item>1918</item>
        <item>1917</item>
        <item>1916</item>
        <item>1915</item>
        <item>1914</item>
        <item>1913</item>
        <item>1912</item>
        <item>1911</item>
        <item>1910</item>
        <item>1909</item>
        <item>1908</item>
        <item>1907</item>
        <item>1906</item>
        <item>1905</item>
        <item>1904</item>
        <item>1903</item>
        <item>1902</item>
        <item>1901</item>
        <item>1900</item>
        <item>1899</item>
        <item>1898</item>
        <item>1897</item>
        <item>1896</item>
        <item>1895</item>
        <item>1894</item>
        <item>1893</item>
        <item>1892</item>
        <item>1891</item>
        <item>1890</item>
        <item>1889</item>
        <item>1888</item>
        <item>1887</item>
        <item>1886</item>
        <item>1885</item>
    </string-array>


    <!-- Record select button text -->
    <string name="engineOilChange">Engine Oil Change Record</string>
    <string name="maintenanceRecord">Maintenance Record</string>
    <string name="partNumbers">Part Numbers</string>

    <!-- Pop-up strings -->
    <string name="wait">Wait!</string>
    <string name="didYouSave">An alteration has been made. Do you want to save the change? If you tap No your changes will be lost</string>
    <string name="didYouSaveNew">Do you want to save the your new entry? If you tap No your new entry will be discarded</string>
    <string name="useUpNav">Use the \"Up\" Arrow at the top left to navigate back.</string>

    <!-- System text -->
    <string name="car_info">Car Info.</string>
    <string name="backup">Backup</string>
    <string name="restore">Restore</string>
    <string name="add_car_name">Add Car</string>
    <string name="help_name">Help</string>
    <string name="car_settings_name">Settings</string>
    <string name="delete_this_car">Delete car</string>
    <string name="delete_part">Delete OEM Part</string>
    <string name="delete_source">Delete This Source</string>
    <string name="edit_oem_part">Edit OEM Part</string>
    <string name="edit_car">Edit Car</string>
    <string name="existing_part">Choose From Existing Part</string>

    <!-- View strings -->
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="make">Make</string>
    <string name="model">Model</string>
    <string name="name">Name</string>
    <string name="source">Source</string>
    <string name="vin">V.I.N.</string>
    <string name="eng_number">Eng. Number</string>
    <string name="eng_size">Eng. Size</string>
    <string name="odo_read">Odometer Reading</string>
    <string name="odom_read">Odometer</string>

    <!-- Oil Change related -->
    <string name="odo_type">Odometer Type</string>
    <string name="oil_interval">Oil Change Interval</string>
    <string name="oil_was_due">Oil Change Was Due</string>
    <string name="next_oil">Next Oil Change Due</string>
    <string name="oil_viscosity">Oil Viscosity</string>
    <string name="oil_brand">Oil Brand</string>
    <string name="oil">Oil</string>
    <string name="filter">Filter</string>
    <string name="no_data">No data.</string>

    <!-- Maintenance related -->
    <string name="work_performed">Work Performed</string>
    <string name="specifics">Specifics</string>
    <string name="miles">Miles</string>
    <string name="click_on_wp">Tap on the maintenance instance to see details of the repair.</string>

    <string name="eng_config">Eng. Configuration</string>
    <string name="eng_config_short">Eng. Config.</string>
    <string name="app_image">app Image</string>

    <string name="save_button">Save</string>
    <string name="view_parts_button">View Parts</string>
    <string name="year_field">Year</string>
    <string name="unit_field">Units</string>
    <string name="notes">Notes:</string>
    <string name="add_part">Add Part</string>
    <string name="part_name">Part Name</string>
    <string name="part_number">Part Number</string>
    <string name="oem_part_number">OEM Part Number</string>
    <string name="mfg">Manufacture</string>
    <string name="barcode">UPC</string>
    <string name="other_sources">Other Sources of This Part</string>
    <string name="move_part">Move Part</string>
    <string name="details">Details:</string>
    <string name="edit_part">Edit Part</string>
    <string name="email">E-mail</string>
    <string name="date">Date</string>

    <!-- Editing string -->
    <string name="enable_edit">Enable Editing</string>
    <string name="to_edit">To edit selection, enable editing\nfrom the drop down menu.</string>

    <!-- "Are You Sure . . . -->
    <string name="are_you_sure">Are You Sure?</string>
    <string name="not_reversible_part">Deleting this part is permanent and irreversible.</string>
    <string name="not_reversible_source">Deleting this part source is permanent and irreversible.</string>
    <string name="not_reversible_car">Deleting this car is permanent and irreversible.</string>
    <string name="tapSave">Tap the save button</string>
    <string name="tapSaveNoArrow">Tap the save button</string>

    <string name="date_format">EEE, ddMMMyyyy</string>
    <string name="textView">TextView</string>

    <string name="year_hint">Year</string>


    <!-- Permissions explanation -->
    <string name="permissions_explanation">
        This app utilizes a light-weight embedded databasing system to store
        your car and part information. This section of the app is to give you a means of backing-up and
        restoring your information in.\n\n

        It\'s important to backup your data so as to prevent a lose
        of what will sure to be, over time, a large accumulation of parts and their additional sources.
        This lose of your information could be due to the lose or damage of your phone or tablet.\n\n

        Tap the E-mail button below to directly email us with your preference in cloud drive sites.\n\n

        Read the Help in the drop-down menu above for more information.
    </string>


    <!-- Help Texts -->
    <string name="MainActivity_help">
        <![CDATA[
        <h3>Welcome to MyClassicCar.</h3>

        <p>This application is aimed at aiding classic car owners to help them keep track their car\'s maintenance and have a handy database of
            difficult to find parts for their cars with part numbers. Often times Parts Store databases
            don\'t go back much before the 1970\'s making it difficult to locate needed parts. With this app
            a person can supply a part number to a parts counter person for cross referencing. Making it easier
            to locate the needed part.
            </p>

        <h5>App Hierarchy</h5>
            <u>The App hierarchy is as follows:</u><br/>
            &#9679; List of Vehicles.<br/>
            &emsp;&#9679; Oil change record for a specific Vehicle.<br/>
            &emsp;&#9679; Repair record for a specific Vehicle.<br/>
            &emsp;&#9679; List of parts for a specific Vehicle.<br/>
            &emsp;&emsp;&#9679; List of additional Sources for<br/>
            &emsp;&emsp;&ensp;a specific part over and above the<br/>
            &emsp;&emsp;&ensp;vehicle manufacture.<br/>

        <h5>Getting Started</h5>
            <p>To get started with your freshly loaded <i>My Classic Car</i>, tap the
            plus sign in the Home view and enter the basic information for your car,
            then tap save. The minimum information is \"Make\", \"Year\", and \"Oil Change Interval\"
            mileage. Enter as many cars as you would like. During the Save process you will be
            redirected back to the Home view,
            which is where a listing of cars is maintained. Once back in the Home view, tap
            on the cell for the car you want to add a part to or record a maintenance or oil change incident.
            </p>

        <h5>Oil and Maintenance Records</h5>
            <p>First tap on the desired car. Then tap on either the \"Oil Change Record\" button
            or the \"Oil Maintenance Record\" button. from there tap on the Plus Sign
            at the lower right side of the screen to enter a new
            record. These records are only editable after you enable editing from the
            drop down menu.
            </p>

        <h5>Parts Database</h5>
            <p>First tap on the desired car. Then tap on the \"Part Numbers\" button.
            From there tap the Plus sign at the lower right side of the screen to enter a part for this car
            \u2014 an indication of which car you are adding a part for will be posted
            in the toolbar at the top of the view. Tap on the Question Mark \"<b>?</b>\"
            at the top of the view for assistance and details on adding parts.
            </p>

        <h5>Making Changes to a Car</h5>
            <p>If you make a typo, you can correct it by tapping on the Car in the list
            in the Home view that needs the correction. At the top of the next view
            \u2014 which is the selection view \u2014 tap on the small Car icon in the toolbar.
            This will take you to the Car Info view. From this view tap on the pencil
            button to edit. Be sure to tap Save once you have finished editing.
            </p>

        <h5>Credits</h5>
        <u>Thanks to:</u><br/>
            &#9679; Google for creating Android and Android Studio. <br/>
            &#9679; Jet Brains for producing the IntelliJ base for Android Studio.<br/>
            &#9679; SQLite for their open source embedded DBMS.<br/>
         ]]>
    </string>


    <string name="AddCarActivity_help">
        <![CDATA[
        <h5>Adding a Car</h5>
        <p>The fields here are generally self explanatory. The minimum requirement information
        for saving a car is \"<b>Make</b>\", \"<b>Year</b>\", and \"<b>Oil Change Interval</b> mileage\".
        (Mileage between oil changes)
        </p>

        <h5>Include a Photo</h5>
        <p>A photo can be included with your listing by tapping on the square,
        \"No Image Available\", at the top left corner of the view. This will
        activate the device camera. Try to center the car in the photo for the
        best possible thumbnail image. A photo is not requires for the entry of
        a car. After snapping a photo many camera apps will require you to tap
        a \"Save\" button, to accept the photo. Sometimes that \"Save\" button
        will be in the form of a check mark.</p>

        <h5>Be Sure to Save</h5>
        <p>Save your freshly entered car by simply tapping on the green button
        \u2014 the Save button \u2014 at the lower left of the view.
        Once saved you will be returned to the Home view
        where you will see your newly entered car.</p>

        <h5>Making Changes</h5>
        <p>If you make a typo, you can correct it by tapping on the car in the list
        in the Home view that needs the correction. From the next view
        \u2014 which is the Record Selection view \u2014 tap on the small car icon
        in the toolbar. This will take you to a view displaying your car\'s info.
        Now tap on the pencil button to edit. Be sure to tap Save once you have finished editing.</p>

        ]]>
    </string>


    <string name="RecordSelectActivity_help">
                <![CDATA[
        <h5>App Structure</h5>

            <u>The App hierarchy is as follows:</u><br/>
            &#9679; List of Vehicles.<br/>
            &emsp;&#9679; Oil change record for a specific Vehicle.<br/>
            &emsp;&#9679; Repair record for a specific Vehicle.<br/>
            &emsp;&#9679; List of parts for a specific Vehicle.<br/>
            &emsp;&emsp;&#9679; List of additional Sources for<br/>
            &emsp;&emsp;&ensp;a specific part over and above the<br/>
            &emsp;&emsp;&ensp;vehicle manufacture.<br/>
            ]]>
    </string>


    <string name="ViewPartActivity_help">
        <![CDATA[

            <h5>OEM Parts</h5>
            <p>The parts that are or will be presented here are intended to be
            parts from a car manufacture, often referred to as OEM parts. These can be seen as the
            \"<b>root</b>\" part, providing a listing for, lets say, an Air Filter.
            Once you have entered a part tap on the desired part you want to see the information for. It is in the next
            view you can add additional sources for that part.</p>


            <h5>Add an OEM Part</h5>
            <p>To add an OEM part tap on the plus sign and fill in the information you have.
            A <b>Part Name</b> is required for saving a part \u2014 Name-less parts are not permitted.
            A <b>Part Number</b> is NOT required for creating a part as original manufacture
            part numbers are often not easily obtainable. This will at least get a listing
            started for a part for this car \u2014 an indication of which car you are adding a part for will be posted
            in the toolbar at the top of the view. Be sure to tap the save button when you are
            finished.</p>

            <p>If you didn\'t have the Part Number or other information at the
            time you created the OEM Part listing, you can add it later by edit the
            listing and adding the missing information. Check the help \"<b>?</b>\" in the next
            view for info on viewing and editing an OEM part. </p>

            <h5>Include a Photo</h5>
            <p>When adding or editing an OEM part, a photo can be included or changed by
            simply tapping on the photo square to activate the device camera. Many camera apps
            will require you to tap a \"Save\" button, to accept the photo.
            Sometimes that \"Save\" button will be in the form of a check mark.</p>

            <h5>Map to Existing OEM Parts</h5>
            <p>As an intended feature of this app, after you have entered more than one
            vehicle and OEM parts for those vehicles, you will offered the ability to
            map to an existing part already in storage. Tap on the plus sign to add a part as normal.
            If you choose \"Existing\" you will be presented with a full list of <i>ALL</i> parts in storage except
            for those already mapped to the particular vehicle you are seeking to
            add a part to.</p>

            <p>The premise behind this feature is many cars from the same car manufacture,
            approximately the same age, will often use the same
            part on two different Models of the same brand of vehicles, and often two different brands
            from the same car manufacture. These listings will literally be the same exact
            part in storage, merely mapped to more than one car. So if you edit an OEM
            part while under a specific vehicle, that edit will also appear in the listing
            under the other vehicle(s) this part is mapped to. (So, no, you\'re not going
            crazy.)</p>

            <p>This feature is intended to provide flexibility, save space in storage,
            prevent redundancies, and hopefully prevent confusion.</p>

            <h5>Add Additional Sources</h5>
            <p>Once an "OEM" part is created or mapped to a specific vehicle simply tap on
            the desired part listing to view its details. When viewing a parts details
            \u2014 Single Part view \u2014 tap on the Plus sign to enter additional
            sources for that part.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="SinglePartActivity_help">
        <![CDATA[
            <h5>View OEM Part Info</h5>
            <p>To see the complete OEM part listing tap on either the <b>Part Name</b> or <b>OEM
            Part Number</b> fields to view all the part\'s details, including any added notes or details. </p>

            <h5>Edit OEM Part Information</h5>
            <p>To make a correction or alteration to an OEM part
            first view the part\'s details by tapping on either the <b>Part Name</b> or <b>OEM
            Part Number</b> fields, then tap on the pencil to edit. In Edit mode the photo can
            changed or added by tapping the photo to activate the camera. Be sure to tap Save when finished.</p>

            <h5>Delete an OEM Part</h5>
            <p>Tap on either the <b>Part Name</b> or <b>OEM Part Number</b> fields to enter
            the OEM Part details view. Once there, tap on the drop down menu in the toolbar \u2014 three vertical
            dots. In the drop down menu is a selection called \"Delete OEM Part\".
            This will delete the current OEM part and <i>all</i> of the additional sources listed for this part. Once
            deleted you will be redirected to the view listing the OEM parts for the current
            car less the one you just deleted. If this was a shared part it will only be un-mapped
            to this car and remain in storage and mapped to the other car(s) it was mapped to.
            </p>

            <h5>Add Additional Sources</h5>
            <p>Additional sources are places like Parts Stores, websites, and catalogs, To add an
            additional source for \"this\" part tap on the Plus sign. Add as many additional
            sources as you need to.</p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="BackupActivity_help">
        <![CDATA[
        <h5>Information backup</h5>
        <p>This is the <i>\"quick and dirty\"</i> backup solution. Cloud backup solutions will be implemented
            once it is discovered which cloud drive backup solutions people want to use. E-mail
            pps@woodlandsoftwaresolutions.com with your preference of cloud drive sites by clicking
            the \"E-mail\" button on the Backup view.</p>

        <h5>How To Do a Backup</h5>
        <p>Simply tap the Backup button. A copy of the file where your information is stored will be placed
            in the <b>Documents</b> directory. This makes it possible to have access the database file
            that your app information is stored in. Use the File Manager that accompanies nearly all Android devices to
            look in Internal Storage for a file called \"carParts.db\". You will want to copy the
            \"carParts.db\" file to an off device drive website or location. You could e-mail yourself the file or
            perform a Share on it to an Internet Cloud drive site like Google Drive of DropBox.
            You will have the have the mobile app for your favorite cloud drive site installed on you
            device to do this.</p>

        <h5>Restoring your information</h5>
        <p>If you have changed devices because you are upgrading or because of lose or damage,
            you can restore your PPS data file by first returning your saved information file, \"carParts.db\", to
            your device by e-mailing it to yourself or by saving it to favorite cloud drive site and then exporting or
            saving it to the <b>Download</b> directory in Internal Storage. Most of the time you <i>will not</i>
            have a choice of where your file gets saved to on your device. It will most likely be
            copied to the <b>Download</b> directory, which is why the Download directory was setup in
            this app as the place where the Restore subroutine will go looking for your
            information file at. Simply tap the Restore button to restore your car and parts information
            to the app.</p>

        <p><b>Do not</b> alter your information file while it is in your chosen backup location as
            this will very likely cause inaccessibility to some or most of your stored information and
            possibly app crashes. Data corruption.</p>

        <p>If you received a \"File Not Found\" error statement while trying to perform a Restore
            then your file is not in the correct location on your device. On many devices there is a
            Download directory on both your microSD card and in \"Device Storage\". You want one in
            the Device Storage, which is sometimes called Internal Storage. Use your device\'s File
            Manager app to copy the file to the correct location on your device\'s file system.
            This is currently the only way to restore your app information. </p>
        ]]>
    </string>



</resources>
